Hello English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco and
I'm Erica and today we're
going to be looking at
another kind of science
fiction lesson related to
aliens. That's right and I
think in this lesson we'll
actually have an alien
sighting here at English
Pod. Right an alien encounter.
So we're going to
be learning about
the stars, we're going to be
learning about aliens and UFOs today.
That's right and we're also going to
learn some language that you can use to
describe negative results,
things that happen that are bad.
That's right so
let's start by looking
at vocabulary preview.
Very capillary preview.
Okay we have two words
for you that we're going to
hear in the dialogue and
the first one is constellation.
constellation. constellation.
All right so we've all looked
up in the sky and seen shapes
or figures that are
formed by the stars.
That's right so a constellation
is a group of stars that
makes a shape and has
a name. Right there are a
total of 88 known
constellation so the most
popular ones I think
maybe are the little dipper,
the big dipper, etc. I
never knew you were such
a fan of astronomy
Marco. A little bit. All right
what about the next one?
The next one is Earthlings.
Earthlings. Earthlings. So
Earthlings are people who
live on planet Earth. On
Earth exactly and in the
dialogue we're going to
hear greetings Earthlings.
This is the most
typical phrase that you
will hear in almost
every single alien movie.
Exactly so it's like saying
hello people from Earth.
Yes every single alien in
the world says this phrase.
So those are two words
that we are going to
find in this dialogue
today. So why don't we start
and listen to what happens with our UFO
experience. Oh honey this is so romantic.
I have never seen like
so many stars before.
It's beautiful. See that
constellation there?
That's Orion. And
the very bright star?
Well it's not a star
because it doesn't blink.
That's actually Venus.
What's that big flashy one?
I don't know. I
think it's a UFO.
Treatings Earthlings.
I come from afar.
From a distant galaxy known
only to a few. Why are you here?
Where did you come from?
We have been observing
you for the last
three thousand years.
We have seen the amazing
capacity that humans
have to create such
waters as the Taj Mahal
or massive pieces such
as the Hapner Symphony.
Unfortunately your intelligence
and creativity does not
have that consequence. Your ambition
and desire for more over your downfall.
And we are here to
say your plan from you.
You think you have us figured out? What
gives you the right to come and judge us?
Who are you to play
God with our faith?
Silence human. Is it a
belligerent attitude that has
caused you to pay him anguish among
yourselves? Now you will pay the price.
Well that didn't work out
so well for the Earthlings.
I think the aliens are a little
bit belligerent themselves.
Why don't we start by looking at some
of those difficult words that we might have
found in this dialogue
in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Well
the aliens are using a lot
of language to describe
some of the negative
results that are happening
because of the human's
behavior on Earth, right?
Right. And so one of the
things they said was
that your intelligence and
creativity does not come without
consequence. Consequence.
Without consequence. All
right so the consequence
of an action are
basically the results.
Yes exactly and here the
phrase "without consequence"
suggests the negative
results. All right so the
negative results from
your actions. Very good.
What about our next word?
Well the aliens also talked
about human ambition.
Ambition. Ambition.
So what is ambition exactly?
So ambition is the desire or the
want for things to be
better to improve, to get
rich, to be
technologically advanced.
Okay so to want more. Yep.
You have ambitions in your life,
in your professional
life, in your personal life.
So basically we have
ambition and we have
desires and these are the
reasons for our downfall.
Okay so downfall. Downfall.
Will be your downfall.
So the downfall of something
is something that causes failure.
Okay so the loss
of wealth or the loss
of reputation that it's
it gets ruined. Exactly.
The downfall. We can say
like for example the downfall
of the Roman Empire. Or
you know what this guy is
a great employee but his lack
of ambition was his downfall.
Very good. All right
coming up to our next word.
The alien described
that humans have
a belligerent attitude.
belligerent. belligerent.
All right this is a very
nice word so why don't we
listen to some examples of
how we can use it in context.
Example one. Don't
take that belligerent tone
with me. I don't want to
argue we do. Example two.
Thomas is always so
belligerent. It is impossible
to talk to him. Example
three. Stacy was fired for
her belligerent attitude.
Okay so I can understand
that it means sort of
aggressive having a strong
willingness to fight.
Exactly a belligerent person,
a belligerent attitude,
a belligerent country.
Okay very good and
our last word for today.
English. English. So
to cause great anguish.
To cause a lot of terrible
emotional or physical pain.
Okay so it is a syndrome
of pain of suffering.
Yeah but really intense
suffering. Really intense.
Why don't we give a few
examples. The end of his
marriage caused him great
anguish. Or for example
the loss of his dog
caused him great anguish.
Okay so anguish. All
right so we've covered five
great words on
language takeaway today.
Why don't we move on
now to putting it together.
Putting it together. Okay
we're going to look at
three phrases that we
heard in the dialogue and
see how we can use
them in different contexts.
So the aliens were praising
some of the master pieces
that the humans have
created right. Right.
He said you humans create such
wonders as the Taj Mahal blah blah blah.
Okay so let's
look at this phrase.
Such wonders as. All right so
we have a noun here a wonder.
An amazing thing.
An amazing structure.
Yes. So he says such
wonders as now we can change
this noun and replace
it with another one right.
Yeah we can we can replace
that down with anything.
So why don't we hear a
few examples. Example one.
To finish this house we
need such materials as
cement wood and steel.
Example two. I need to write
a report on a social
topic such as psychology,
health or marriage.
Example three.
Companies have found that
social networking sites such as
Facebook and Twitter are
great marketing opportunities.
So this is a really
useful structure to use
when you want to give
examples of many different things.
Okay and as the
alien was criticizing the
humans the guy said
what gives you the right to
come and judge us. So interesting
phrase what gives you the right.
What gives you the right.
What gives you the right. All
right so if I tell you what gives
you the right to and
then a verb. Yeah.
What am I saying there. You're
basically saying you don't have
the right to do this.
You shouldn't do this.
Why are you doing it or
why do you want to have this
control over me. Yeah so
when would be when would
you use this phrase. If
somebody is trying to
control you or maybe
somebody is judging you or
doing something to you
against your will maybe you
would say what gives you the right to take
my phone away. What gives you the right to
tell me what to do. All
right it's a good phrase to
tell that other person
that they shouldn't do that.
They're doing something
unfair. Unfair okay and our
next phrase is very
similar. Who are you to play
God with our fate. Okay so I
want to look at this to play God.
All right so to play
God is making these
arbitrary decisions like he
is the master of everything.
Right controlling everything.
But this phrase who are
you to. So basically saying you
don't have the power or
authority to do this and you
can use it in exactly
the same way.
Who are you to tell me what to do.
Who are you to take away my phone.
Exactly so you don't
have the power to do this.
Very good. So these
phrases are a little bit
aggressive almost
belligerent wouldn't you say.
A little bit but I guess
if you are being treated
unfair or if you are angry
at a situation it would
be a good phrase to use
to put your point across.
Yes and as we saw these
humans are pretty angry.
So why don't we listen
again as they're telling the
aliens who are you to do this to
us. Oh honey this is so romantic.
I have never seen like
so many stars before.
It's beautiful. See that
constellation there?
That's Orion and the
very bright star? Well
it's not a star because
it doesn't blink.
That's actually Venus.
What's that big flashy one?
I don't know. I think it's a UFO.
Greetings earthlings. I come from afar.
From a distant galaxy known only to a few.
Why are you here?
Where did you come from?
Do we have been observing
you for the last 3000 years?
We have seen you amazing
capacity that humans
have to create such
wonders as the Taj Mahal
or massive pieces such
as the Halfner Symphony.
Unfortunately your intelligence
and creativity does not
come without consequence.
Your ambition and desire
for where we will be
your downfall and we are
here to save your planet
from you. You think you
have us figured out?
What gives you the right
to come and judge us? Who are you to
play God with our fate? Silence human.
Is it a belligerent attitude
that has called you to pay
an anguish among yourselves?
Now you will pay the price.
Okay so UFOs and constellations
and stars and planets.
Have you ever had an
encounter with one of these?
Well definitely not an
encounter with a UFO
but maybe with some of
the wonders of the night sky.
What happened? Well
you know when I was small
I used to have my
vacations up in northern
Canada and because it
was so far away from the
city it was really dark
and you could see all
of these shooting stars
so these stars moving
across the sky and lighting
up the whole sky with
their brightness and it
really is one of the most
beautiful things I've ever
seen. So shooting stars
are like balls of fire that
move across the sky right?
Yeah exactly and I saw
once actually I was in
an astronomy class and
turned around and over the
horizon like at the end
of the sky where the sky
meets the earth I saw
this huge ball of fire
move across the sky
and it looked like it landed
in the field next to
us. It was so close.
Wow that's nice. Yeah pretty
amazing. Well I imagine that it is
really amazing and I
guess Canada is the place to
be when you want
to see these things.
I know we've got like northern lights
we've got shooting stars, lots of stuff.
All right so what
about you guys?
You should tell us if
you've ever seen a shooting
star or a meteor or
something of this type of
astronomy things right? Or even a UFO. All
right so come to our website englishpot.
com be sure to leave your
questions and your comments
and Eric and I are there
to answer any questions
or doubts. Well thanks for downloading
you guys and until next time, goodbye!